<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on ACSA Lab</title>
    <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on ACSA Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2.5 Million-Atom Ab Initio Electronic-Structure Simulation of Complex Metallic Heterostructures with DGDFT</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2022/sc22-million-atom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2022/sc22-million-atom/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Novel U-Like Network for the Segmentation of Thoracic Organs</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2020/isbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2020/isbi/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A review of deep learning-based medical image segmentation methods</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2025/zongshu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2025/zongshu/</guid>
      <description>Medical image segmentation is a crucial component of clinical medical image analysis, aimed at accurately identifying and delineating anatomical structures or regions of interest, such as lesions, within medical images. This provides objective and quantitative support for decision-making in disease diagnosis, treatment planning, and postoperative evaluation. In recent years, the rapid growth of available annotated data has facilitated the swift development of deep learning-based medical image segmentation methods, which demonstrate superior accuracy and robustness compared to traditional segmentation techniques, thereby becoming the mainstream technology in the field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A3PIM: An Automated, Analytic and Accurate Processing-in-Memory Offloader</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2024/date-a3pim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2024/date-a3pim/</guid>
      <description>The performance gap between memory and proces- sor has grown rapidly. Consequently, the energy and wall-clock time costs associated with moving data between the CPU and main memory predominate the overall computational cost. The Processing-in-Memory (PIM) paradigm emerges as a promising architecture that mitigates the need for extensive data movements by strategically positioning computing units proximate to the memory. Despite the abundant efforts devoted to building a robust and highly-available PIM system, identifying PIM-friendly segments of applications poses significant challenges due to the lack of a comprehensive tool to evaluate the intrinsic memory access pattern of the segment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating Parallel First-Principles Excited-State Calculation by Low-Rank Approximation with K-Means Clustering</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2022/icpp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2022/icpp/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI for Quantum Mechanics: High Performance Quantum Many-Body Simulations via Deep Learning</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2022/sc22-aiquantum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2022/sc22-aiquantum/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Efficient Multi-GPU Implementation for Linear-Response Time-Dependent Density Functional Theory</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2020/hpcc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2020/hpcc/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic Segmentation of Target Structures for Total Marrow and Lymphoid Irradiation in Bone Marrow Transplantation</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2022/embc-autoseg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2022/embc-autoseg/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carver: Learning to Reconstruct Right Ventricle from Sparse Multi-View 2D Echocardiograms</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2025/icassp-carver/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2025/icassp-carver/</guid>
      <description>Accurate 3D reconstruction of the right ventricle from multi-view echocardiograms is crucial for the quantitative diagnosis of cardiac diseases. However, existing methods often fail to deliver satisfactory results due to the structural complexity of the right ventricle and the sparsity of non-parallel ultrasound views. In this paper, we propose an efficient reconstruction method named Carver, which redefines 3D reconstruction of the right ventricle as a voxel-wise dense prediction task for the first time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CIExplorer: Microarchitecture-Aware Exploration for Tightly Integrated Custom Instruction</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2025/ics-ciexplorer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2025/ics-ciexplorer/</guid>
      <description>Extending existing architectures with customized instruction extensions is emerging to achieve high performance and energy efficiency for specific applications. Automated discovery of custom instructions (CIs) is well-studied nowadays, which requires exploring combinations of different types and quantities of operations, resulting in a vast search space. However, previous works typically use microarchitecture-agnostic cost models, leading to suboptimal CIs that may degrade performance. They leverage graph isomorphism to reduce area overhead, but few of them consider its potential to benefit performance-oriented exploration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clisp: A Robust Interactive Segmentation Framework for Pathological Images</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2024/embc-hannanwang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2024/embc-hannanwang/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contrast Learning Based Robust Framework for Weakly Supervised Medical Image Segmentation with Coarse Bounding Box Annotations</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2023/miccai-cmmca/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2023/miccai-cmmca/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DARNet: Dual-Attention Residual Network for Automatic Diagnosis of COVID-19 via CT Images</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2021/bibm-darnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2021/bibm-darnet/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DB-SpGEMM: A Massively Distributed Block-Sparse Matrix-Matrix Multiplication for Linear-Scaling DFT Calculations</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2024/icpp-zhongzheng/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2024/icpp-zhongzheng/</guid>
      <description>Linear-scaling O(N) density functional theory (DFT) represents a significant advancement in the field of computational materials science, especially for simulations of large systems where traditional cubic-scaling methods become computationally prohibitive. The core operation in O(N) methods is sparse general matrix-matrix multiplication (SpGEMM), which is the major performance bottleneck. To enhance the computational efficiency of SpGEMM, it is crucial to consider the inherent sparse pattern of these matrices. Targeting block-sparse matrices with moderate block sizes and regular block shapes, we have developed a distributed block-sparse matrix-matrix multiplication (DB-SpGEMM) algorithm for large-scale DFT calculations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep learning promoted target volumes delineation of total marrow and total lymphoid irradiation for accelerated radiotherapy: A multi-institutional study</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2024/physicamedica-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2024/physicamedica-study/</guid>
      <description>Background and purpose One of the current roadblocks to the widespread use of Total Marrow Irradiation (TMI) and Total Marrow and Lymphoid Irradiation (TMLI) is the challenging difficulties in tumor target contouring workflow. This study aims to develop a hybrid neural network model that promotes accurate, automatic, and rapid segmentation of multi-class clinical target volumes. Materials and methods Patients who underwent TMI and TMLI from January 2018 to May 2022 were included.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Establishing a Modeling System in 3-km Horizontal Resolution for Global Atmospheric Circulation triggered by Submarine Volcanic Eruptions with 400 Billion Smoothed Particle Hydrodynamics</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2023/sc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2023/sc/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extending the limit of LR-TDDFT on two different approaches: Numerical algorithms and new Sunway heterogeneous supercomputer</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2024/parallelcomputing-qingcaijiang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2024/parallelcomputing-qingcaijiang/</guid>
      <description>First-principles time-dependent density functional theory (TDDFT) is a powerful tool to accurately describe the excited-state properties of molecules and solids in condensed matter physics, computational chemistry, and materials science. However, a perceived drawback in TDDFT calculations is its ultrahigh computational cost O(N^5~N^6) and large memory usage O(N^4) especially for plane-wave basis set, confining its applications to large systems containing thousands of atoms. Here, we present a massively parallel implementation of linear-response TDDFT (LR-TDDFT) and accelerate LR-TDDFT in two different aspects: (1) numerical algorithms on the X86 supercomputer and (2) optimizations on the heterogeneous architecture of the new Sunway supercomputer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FcTC-UNet: Fine-grained Combination of Transformer and CNN for Thoracic Organs Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2022/embc-fctc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2022/embc-fctc/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting the eddying ocean with a deep neural network</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2025/nature-forecasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2025/nature-forecasting/</guid>
      <description>Mesoscale eddies with horizontal scales from tens to hundreds of kilometers are ubiquitous in the upper ocean, dominating the ocean variability from daily to weekly time scales. Their turbulent nature causes great scientific challenges and computational burdens in accurately forecasting the short-term evolution of the ocean states based on conventional physics-driven numerical models. Recently, artificial intelligence (AI)-based methods have achieved competitive forecast performance and greatly increased computational efficiency in weather forecasts, compared to numerical models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FRNET: An Effective Hybrid Structure for Automatic Segmentation of Head and Neck Primary Tumors from Multimodal Images</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2023/isbi-frnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2023/isbi-frnet/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>H-DenseFormer: An Efficient Hybrid Densely Connected Transformer for Multimodal Tumor Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2023/miccai-hdenseformer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2023/miccai-hdenseformer/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-level Load Balancing Strategies for Massively Parallel Smoothed Particle Hydrodynamics Simulation</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2024/icpp-yizhang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2024/icpp-yizhang/</guid>
      <description>In the field of computational fluid dynamics, Smoothed Particle Hydrodynamics (SPH) serves as a powerful tool for investigating complex fluid interactions and instabilities. For the practical SPH simulation of large-scale fluid phenomena such as tsunamis, volcanic eruptions, and planetary collisions, it typically requires billions of particles, as the numerical resolution increases proportionally with the number of particles. To efficiently conduct large-scale SPH simulations on modern supercomputers with massive many-core processors, we propose a novel SPH implementation leveraging multi-level parallelism and a corresponding three-level load balancing strategy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NDFT: Accelerating Density Functional Theory Calculations via Hardware/Software Co-Design on Near-Data Computing System</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2025/dac-ndft/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2025/dac-ndft/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NDPage: Efficient Address Translation for Near-Data Processing Architectures via Tailored Page Table</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2025/date25-ndpage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2025/date25-ndpage/</guid>
      <description>Near-Data Processing (NDP) has been a promising architectural paradigm to address the memory wall problem for data-intensive applications. Practical implementation of NDP architectures calls for system support for better programmability, where having virtual memory (VM) is critical. Modern computing systems incorporate a 4-level page table design to support address translation in VM. However, simply adopting an existing 4-level page table in NDP systems causes significant address translation overhead because (1) NDP applications generate a lot of address translations, and (2) the limited L1 cache in NDP systems cannot cover the accesses to page table entries (PTEs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predictive Accuracy-Based Active Learning for Medical Image Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2024/ijcai-shijun/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2024/ijcai-shijun/</guid>
      <description>Active learning is considered a viable solution to alleviate the contradiction between the high dependency of deep learning-based segmentation methods on annotated data and the expensive pixel-level annotation cost of medical images. However, most existing methods suffer from unreliable uncertainty assessment and the struggle to balance diversity and informativeness, leading to poor performance in segmentation tasks. In response, we propose an efficient Predictive Accuracy-based Active Learning (PAAL) method for medical image segmentation, first introducing predictive accuracy to define uncertainty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PromptSeg: Learning to Segment Medical Image via Visual Prompts</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2025/icassp-promptseg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2025/icassp-promptseg/</guid>
      <description>Deep learning has made remarkable medical image segmentation advancements, yet its generalization capability across tasks remains challenging. The variety of task objectives, disease-dependent labeling variations, and multi-center data contribute to the poor generalization capacity of task-specific models on unseen tasks, necessitating domain adaptation or fine-tuning. This typically involves data annotation and network retraining, limiting the application of deep learning in clinical practice. In this study, we propose PromptSeg, an innovative Transformer-based unified segmentation framework for general medical image segmentation tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pruner: A Draft-then-Verify Exploration Mechanism to Accelerate Tensor Program Tuning</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2025/asplos-pruner/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2025/asplos-pruner/</guid>
      <description>Tensor program tuning is essential for the efficient deployment of deep neural networks. Search-based approaches have demonstrated scalability and effectiveness in automatically finding high-performance programs for specific hardware. However, the search process is often inefficient, taking hours or even days to discover optimal programs due to the exploration mechanisms guided by an accurate but slow-learned cost model. Meanwhile, the learned cost model trained on one platform cannot seamlessly adapt online to another, which we call cross-platform online unawareness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PWDFT-SW: Extending the Limit of Plane-Wave DFT Calculations to 16K Atoms on the New Sunway Supercomputer</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2025/tpds-pwdft-sw/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2025/tpds-pwdft-sw/</guid>
      <description>First-principles density functional theory (DFT) with plane wave (PW) basis set is the most widely used method in quantum mechanical material simulations due to its advantages in accuracy and universality. However, a perceived drawback of PW-based DFT calculations is their substantial computational cost and memory usage, which currently limits their ability to simulate large-scale complex systems containing thousands of atoms. This situation is exacerbated in the new Sunway supercomputer, where each process is limited to a mere 16 GB of memory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantifying Throughput of Basic Blocks on ARM Microarchitectures by Static Code Analyzers: A Case Study on Kunpeng 920</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2022/hpcc22-sca/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2022/hpcc22-sca/</guid>
      <description>The performance of high-performance computing (HPC) and other real-world applications is becoming unpre-dictable as the micro-architecture of the modern central processing unit (CPU) turns to be more and more complex. As a consequence, predicting the execution time of a code snippet is notoriously difficult. Basic block throughput predictor, also known as static code analyzer, provides a ubiquitous way to predict the execution time of a basic block, which includes assembly code segments without jump-related instructions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RDMA-Based Apache Storm for High-Performance Stream Data Processing</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2021/ijpp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2021/ijpp/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking Automatic Segmentation of Gross Target Volume from a Decoupling Perspective</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2023/cmig-autoseg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2023/cmig-autoseg/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simultaneous Right Ventricle End-diastolic and End-systolic Frame Identification and Landmark Detection on Echocardiography</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2021/embc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2021/embc/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>swMPAS-A: Scaling MPAS-A to 39 Million Heterogeneous Cores on the New Generation Sunway Supercomputer</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2022/tpds-swmpas-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2022/tpds-swmpas-a/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SWSPH: A Massively Parallel SPH Implementation for Hundred-Billion-Particle Simulation on New Sunway Supercomputer</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2023/euro-par/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2023/euro-par/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncovering the performance bottleneck of modern HPC processor with static code analyzer: a case study on Kunpeng 920</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2023/thpc-sca/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2023/thpc-sca/</guid>
      <description>The performance gap between memory and proces- sor has grown rapidly. Consequently, the energy and wall-clock time costs associated with moving data between the CPU and main memory predominate the overall computational cost. The Processing-in-Memory (PIM) paradigm emerges as a promising architecture that mitigates the need for extensive data movements by strategically positioning computing units proximate to the memory. Despite the abundant efforts devoted to building a robust and highly-available PIM system, identifying PIM-friendly segments of applications poses significant challenges due to the lack of a comprehensive tool to evaluate the intrinsic memory access pattern of the segment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whole Slide Image Multi-Classification of Cervical Epithelial Lesions Based on Unsupervised Pre-training</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2022/embc-whole/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2022/embc-whole/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>