<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on ACSA Lab</title>
    <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on ACSA Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2.5 Million-Atom Ab Initio Electronic-Structure Simulation of Complex Metallic Heterostructures with DGDFT</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2022/sc22-million-atom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2022/sc22-million-atom/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Novel U-Like Network for the Segmentation of Thoracic Organs</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2020/isbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2020/isbi/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A3PIM: An Automated, Analytic and Accurate Processing-in-Memory Offloader</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2024/date-a3pim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2024/date-a3pim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The performance gap between memory and proces-&#xA;sor has grown rapidly. Consequently, the energy and wall-clock&#xA;time costs associated with moving data between the CPU and&#xA;main memory predominate the overall computational cost. The&#xA;Processing-in-Memory (PIM) paradigm emerges as a promising&#xA;architecture that mitigates the need for extensive data movements&#xA;by strategically positioning computing units proximate to the&#xA;memory. Despite the abundant efforts devoted to building a&#xA;robust and highly-available PIM system, identifying PIM-friendly&#xA;segments of applications poses significant challenges due to the&#xA;lack of a comprehensive tool to evaluate the intrinsic memory&#xA;access pattern of the segment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating Parallel First-Principles Excited-State Calculation by Low-Rank Approximation with K-Means Clustering</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2022/icpp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2022/icpp/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI for Quantum Mechanics: High Performance Quantum Many-Body Simulations via Deep Learning</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2022/sc22-aiquantum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2022/sc22-aiquantum/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Efficient Multi-GPU Implementation for Linear-Response Time-Dependent Density Functional Theory</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2020/hpcc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2020/hpcc/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automatic Segmentation of Target Structures for Total Marrow and Lymphoid Irradiation in Bone Marrow Transplantation</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2022/embc-autoseg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2022/embc-autoseg/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clisp: A Robust Interactive Segmentation Framework for Pathological Images</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2024/embc-hannanwang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2024/embc-hannanwang/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contrast Learning Based Robust Framework for Weakly Supervised Medical Image Segmentation with Coarse Bounding Box Annotations</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2023/miccai-cmmca/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2023/miccai-cmmca/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DARNet: Dual-Attention Residual Network for Automatic Diagnosis of COVID-19 via CT Images</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2021/bibm-darnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2021/bibm-darnet/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DB-SpGEMM: A Massively Distributed Block-Sparse Matrix-Matrix Multiplication for Linear-Scaling DFT Calculations</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2024/icpp-zhongzheng/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2024/icpp-zhongzheng/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Linear-scaling O(N) density functional theory (DFT) represents a significant advancement in the field of computational materials science, especially for simulations of large systems where traditional cubic-scaling methods become computationally prohibitive. The core operation in O(N) methods is sparse general matrix-matrix multiplication (SpGEMM), which is the major performance bottleneck. To enhance the computational efficiency of SpGEMM, it is crucial to consider the inherent sparse pattern of these matrices. Targeting block-sparse matrices with moderate block sizes and regular block shapes, we have developed a distributed block-sparse matrix-matrix multiplication (DB-SpGEMM) algorithm for large-scale DFT calculations. Through deep optimizations in distributed matrix storage, computational task decomposition, asynchronous task scheduling, and load balancing, we have implemented a linear-scaling method based on this algorithm within the discontinuous Galerkin density functional theory (DGDFT). On the new Sunway supercomputer, our approach achieves a 8 ∼ 10x speedup compared to the original version on monolayer phosphorene systems, and demonstrates superior scalability.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Establishing a Modeling System in 3-km Horizontal Resolution for Global Atmospheric Circulation triggered by Submarine Volcanic Eruptions with 400 Billion Smoothed Particle Hydrodynamics</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2023/sc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2023/sc/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extending the limit of LR-TDDFT on two different approaches: Numerical algorithms and new Sunway heterogeneous supercomputer</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2024/parallelcomputing-qingcaijiang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2024/parallelcomputing-qingcaijiang/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First-principles time-dependent density functional theory (TDDFT) is a powerful tool to accurately describe the excited-state properties of molecules and solids in condensed matter physics, computational chemistry, and materials science. However, a perceived drawback in TDDFT calculations is its ultrahigh computational cost O(N^5~N^6) and large memory usage O(N^4) especially for plane-wave basis set, confining its applications to large systems containing thousands of atoms. Here, we present a massively parallel implementation of linear-response TDDFT (LR-TDDFT) and accelerate LR-TDDFT in two different aspects: (1) numerical algorithms on the X86 supercomputer and (2) optimizations on the heterogeneous architecture of the new Sunway supercomputer. Furthermore, we carefully design the parallel data and task distribution schemes to accommodate the physical nature of different computation steps. By utilizing these two different methods, our implementation can gain an overall speedup of 10x and 80x and efficiently scales to large systems up to 4096 and 2744 atoms within dozens of seconds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FcTC-UNet: Fine-grained Combination of Transformer and CNN for Thoracic Organs Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2022/embc-fctc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2022/embc-fctc/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FRNET: An Effective Hybrid Structure for Automatic Segmentation of Head and Neck Primary Tumors from Multimodal Images</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2023/isbi-frnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2023/isbi-frnet/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>H-DenseFormer: An Efficient Hybrid Densely Connected Transformer for Multimodal Tumor Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2023/miccai-hdenseformer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2023/miccai-hdenseformer/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multi-level Load Balancing Strategies for Massively Parallel Smoothed Particle Hydrodynamics Simulation</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2024/icpp-yizhang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2024/icpp-yizhang/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the field of computational fluid dynamics, Smoothed Particle Hydrodynamics (SPH) serves as a powerful tool for investigating complex fluid interactions and instabilities. For the practical SPH simulation of large-scale fluid phenomena such as tsunamis, volcanic eruptions, and planetary collisions, it typically requires billions of particles, as the numerical resolution increases proportionally with the number of particles. To efficiently conduct large-scale SPH simulations on modern supercomputers with massive many-core processors, we propose a novel SPH implementation leveraging multi-level parallelism and a corresponding three-level load balancing strategy. Our load balancing approach comprises: (1) a process-level domain decomposition algorithm based on an improved 1D partitioning exact algorithm; (2) an adaptive recursive cell subdivision method; (3) a fine-grained dynamic thread-level task scheduling strategy. Our experiment uses 1 billion particles to simulate converging Richtmyer–Meshkov instability and verifies the effect of load balancing on new Sunway supercomputer. As the shockwave converges on the central interface area, our load balancing strategy breaks the bottleneck constraints on the slowest node, increases the balance of computational loads between nodes from 30.01% to 91.48%, and achieves a 2.8 × improvement in computational performance. Finally, our implementation enables each CPU to handle 10 million particles and scale from 1 CPU to 100,000 CPUs (in total 39 million cores with 1 trillion particles) with a performance of 80.4% parallel efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predictive Accuracy-Based Active Learning for Medical Image Segmentation</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2024/ijcai-shijun/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2024/ijcai-shijun/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Active learning is considered a viable solution to alleviate the contradiction between the high dependency of deep learning-based segmentation methods on annotated data and the expensive pixel-level annotation cost of medical images. However, most existing methods suffer from unreliable uncertainty assessment and the struggle to balance diversity and informativeness, leading to poor performance in segmentation tasks. In response, we propose an efficient Predictive Accuracy-based Active Learning (PAAL) method for medical image segmentation, first introducing predictive accuracy to define uncertainty. Specifically, PAAL mainly consists of an Accuracy Predictor (AP) and a Weighted Polling Strategy (WPS). The former is an attached learnable module that can accurately predict the segmentation accuracy of unlabeled samples relative to the target model with the predicted posterior probability. The latter provides an efficient hybrid querying scheme by combining predicted accuracy and feature representation, aiming to ensure the uncertainty and diversity of the acquired samples. Extensive experiment results on multiple datasets demonstrate the superiority of PAAL. PAAL achieves comparable accuracy to fully annotated data while reducing annotation costs by approximately 50% to 80%, showcasing significant potential in clinical applications. The code is available at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/shijun18/PAAL-MedSeg&#34;&gt;https://github.com/shijun18/PAAL-MedSeg&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantifying Throughput of Basic Blocks on ARM Microarchitectures by Static Code Analyzers: A Case Study on Kunpeng 920</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2022/hpcc22-sca/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2022/hpcc22-sca/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The performance of high-performance computing (HPC) and other real-world applications is becoming unpre-dictable as the micro-architecture of the modern central processing unit (CPU) turns to be more and more complex. As a consequence, predicting the execution time of a code snippet is notoriously difficult. Basic block throughput predictor, also known as static code analyzer, provides a ubiquitous way to predict the execution time of a basic block, which includes assembly code segments without jump-related instructions. In this article, we build a workflow to faithfully run, collect and analyze basic blocks from real-world applications. Several static code analyzers are introduced, compared and optimized to show which one performs better on accuracy and other metrics on Kunpeng 920 processor. Under extensive experiments, we achieve state-of-the-art 86.7% accuracy in predicting the throughput of all basic …&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RDMA-Based Apache Storm for High-Performance Stream Data Processing</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2021/ijpp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2021/ijpp/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rethinking Automatic Segmentation of Gross Target Volume from a Decoupling Perspective</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2023/cmig-autoseg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2023/cmig-autoseg/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simultaneous Right Ventricle End-diastolic and End-systolic Frame Identification and Landmark Detection on Echocardiography</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2021/embc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2021/embc/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SWSPH: A Massively Parallel SPH Implementation for Hundred-Billion-Particle Simulation on New Sunway Supercomputer</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2023/euro-par/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2023/euro-par/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uncovering the performance bottleneck of modern HPC processor with static code analyzer: a case study on Kunpeng 920</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2023/thpc-sca/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2023/thpc-sca/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The performance gap between memory and proces-&#xA;sor has grown rapidly. Consequently, the energy and wall-clock&#xA;time costs associated with moving data between the CPU and&#xA;main memory predominate the overall computational cost. The&#xA;Processing-in-Memory (PIM) paradigm emerges as a promising&#xA;architecture that mitigates the need for extensive data movements&#xA;by strategically positioning computing units proximate to the&#xA;memory. Despite the abundant efforts devoted to building a&#xA;robust and highly-available PIM system, identifying PIM-friendly&#xA;segments of applications poses significant challenges due to the&#xA;lack of a comprehensive tool to evaluate the intrinsic memory&#xA;access pattern of the segment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Whole Slide Image Multi-Classification of Cervical Epithelial Lesions Based on Unsupervised Pre-training</title>
      <link>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2022/embc-whole/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://acsa.ustc.edu.cn/publications/2022/embc-whole/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
